好了
Well,
现在全玩完了
it's all going to shit.
炼金男爵一个一个的都想控制黑巷
Chembarons warring for control of the Lanes.
地痞混混因为一口剩饭都能打起来
Wannabe street thugs squabbling over scraps.
就像范德尔没了的时候一样
Just like when Vander shoved off.
只是这次
Except this time...
你不能出来主持大局了
you aren't here to put it all back together,
因为...
because...
你已经被我打成筛子了
Because someone put all those holes in you.
蔚总说我什么都能修得好
Vi used to say I could fix anything.
而我却把一切都毁了
Before I broke everything.
她还说过好多话
She used to say a lot.
你跟她一样
Her and you.
你们总对我呼来喝去的
Always bossing me around.
如今倒是清净了
Now it's so quiet.
我反倒不适应了
What am I supposed to do with that?
你受够了没有
Have you had enough?
《英雄联盟:双城之战》
第二季第二集
本WEB版外挂字幕由  风吹来的那片云  双语合并
你能懂吗
You feel it?
脑子里
That...
不停地响个没完
...buzzing behind your eyes?
但只要轻轻来这么一下 像这样
Because you know, in a moment, it could all...
砰
poow!
那感觉才叫一个爽
Best feeling in the world, kid.
(金克丝 通缉)
对啊 那是我
Yep, that's me.
你要是哪一天对这个世界 或者亲人厌了 烦了
You ever need to curse a sibling or a family or a society...
找我
my card.
那什么 咱就说 就事论事啊
Well, you know, far be it from me,
就是您雇我 是要我来管账
but, uh, you hired me to run the numbers.
可自打咱们跟其他炼金男爵杠上之后
And ever since we've gone up against the other chembarons,
- 账面就变得... - 更难看了
- the numbers are in the, uh... - Shitter?
倒也不是更难看了
Not exactly the term I...
知道你这种动脑子的
Ever wonder why fat brains
为什么最后要给动拳头的干活吗
like you always wind up working for grunts like me?
不 不知道
No, uh, never.
你们的脑子只动了一半
You only use half your head.
出出主意啊
Plotting moves.
计算计算结果啊
Calculating odds.
希尔科凭什么能拿下黑巷
Know how Silco took hold of the Lanes?
凭的是拳头够硬
With his bare teeth.
可是 现在出拳是不是有点草率
It just, you know, seems, uh, hasty.
玛戈的老巢少说也得有十个打手坐镇
Last count, Margot had at least ten hitters guarding the stash.
玛戈和克罗斯随便怎么折腾
Margot and Chross can buck all they want, but in the end,
反正最终都是我笑到最后
I'll be the one smiling.
在我当上老大之前 你就管一样
Until I'm in Silco's chair, your only job
就是保证咱们有钱花
is to make the numbers work, hmm?
灰瘴都进到这儿了
The Grey. All the way up here?
你懂个屁
What do you know?
灰瘴清了场
Cleared the place out.
那咱们反倒还省事儿了
Might have made our jobs a lot easier.
别 别去
No, no, no. We can't.
不过就是地下工厂的废气嘛
It's factory smog trapped underground.
- 瞧把你给吓得 - 老大
- No more, no less. - Boss.
你先进去 看看情况
You-- You go on ahead. Report back.
我
Me?
我知道你们都在盘算着 怎么怎么锯掉另外几个人的脑袋
I know you're all fantasizing about sawing each other's heads off.
那干脆我就直说了吧
So I'm gonna get right to it.
现在不是争地盘的时候
These turf wars have to stop.
是他们两个先挑事儿的
These two have been the aggressors.
我不过是正当防卫
I've only defended my interests.
你可别在这装模作样了
Playing coy doesn't suit you, love.
也不知道是谁先突袭升天走廊的
You started this dance when you raided the Rapturewalk.
我要你那条破烂大街干什么
What could I want with your boulevard of filth?
咱们的敌人是上城
Topside is the real enemy.
这时候他们就希望看到咱们自相残杀
Us killing each other is playing right into their hands.
你们那些纠缠不清的恩怨 能不能先放一放
Our best shot is to put aside these petty squabbles
大家联手御敌
and join forces.
跟他们俩联手
Ally with these two?
我宁可一个人跟上城拼一拼
I rather favor my chances with Topside.
就算联手
Even together,
我们的人也比上城少得多
they outnumber us four to one.
算上这阵子死伤的就更少了
That's before all the recent casualties.
虽然他们人多
Might matter up there,
但是在裂沟作战
but they don't know the first thing
输赢可就不一定了
about fighting in the fissures.
他没死吧
Is he dead?
怎么一直不吭声啊
Why is he so quiet?
她说得对
She's right.
只有拔掉上城这根刺才能安宁
We don't get Topside off our backs, we don't last.
不过我有我的想法
But I got a different solution.
把金克丝交出来
We give them Jinx.
问题就解决了
It's all they really want.
(金克丝 皮尔特沃夫 通缉)
我们不能把自己人交出去
We don't hand over our people.
我们  你也就剩张嘴能动了还代表我们
"We"? You don't do much of anything anymore, do you, magpie?
那掉了毛的凤凰可不如鸡啊
Bird without a wing's just a funny-looking rat.
被说中了 是不是啊
Struck a nerve, did I?
行了 咱们做笔生意
Okay, I'll make you a deal.
你替我帮咱们上城的朋友 找到那蓝发小妞
You help me put a bow on Baby Blue for our friends upstairs,
我就给你弄个新机械手臂
I'll cut you a brand-new puncher,
配置什么的 都是最尖儿的
top of the line, all the fixings.
考虑考虑 但我先说好
Think on it. But I promise,
你可就这么一次机会
it's the last offer you're gonna get.
为什么你人都死了
I can't believe you're dead
我还得继续为你收拾烂摊子
and I'm still mopping up your messes.
大姐 你没病吧
Jeez, lady, you crazy?
跟死人说话呢
Talking to dead people.
你是来给我个了断的吗
You here to finish me off?
嫌我照顾你的还不够啊
Haven't I done you enough favors?
每天这个时候
Same time every day.
多大的人了 自己还搞不定
Big baby couldn't do it himself.
他也不用亲自上手
- Couldn't do much himself. - Mm.
每天一到这个时候 就会派我去黑巷替他收账
About now, he'd have me all over the Lanes running his collections.
替他造武器
Building his weapons.
替他谈生意
Making his deals.
替他炸飞他的仇家
Exploding his enemies.
他人不在了
He dips out,
整个世界也一团乱
the whole world flips over.
他的抱负
All his plans.
我们建立起来的一切
Everything we built.
现在到底要怎么办才好
The hell we supposed to do now?
任它化为灰烬
Watch it all burn.
我说什么来着
What'd I tell you?
维克托
Viktor.
Viktor! Viktor... Viktor!
杰斯
Jayce?
维克托
Viktor?
我的天
My God.
我是怎么了
What... am I?
你...
You're...
你没事了
You're alive.
You're-- You're alive.
你身上冷不冷
You must be cold.
冷...
Cold.
不 并不冷
No, I don't think so.
感觉像被能量充斥
I sense a charge.
像能量场 循环的脉冲
A potential. A recursive impulse.
不舒服 但不能用冷形容
Unpleasant, but... "cold" isn't its name.
是海克斯核心...
The Hexcore.
维克托它救了你
Viktor, it saved you.
不知怎么 它跟你融为一体
Somehow it-- It adapted to your injuries,
不断地改变 进化
changing and evolving.
感觉你们心灵相通了
It was as if it was connected to you.
我参照了你治腿的笔记
I did my best using the notes from your leg.
能记的也都记了
Recorded everything.
还有很多疑问 不过...
There are still so many questions, but--
我应该死掉的
I was supposed to die.
你答应销毁海克斯核心的
You promised to destroy the Hexcore.
不 你不明白吗
No. Don't you see?
黑默丁格错了
Heimerdinger was wrong.
我们都错了
We were wrong.
它并没有那么可怕...
It's not as bad as we--
它害死了斯凯 杰斯
It killed Sky, Jayce.
什么
What?
不
No.
她和我们有着...
She had such dreams.
有着同样的梦想
As did we once.
我打算去向议会递辞呈
I'm going to resign from the Council.
现在我明白了
I understand now.
我就应该在这里
My place was always here
在实验室跟你一起
in the lab with you.
咱们一起努力 都会好的
We'll make this right. Together.
我必须与你和这个地方道别了 杰斯
I must say goodbye to this place now. To you.
道别
Goodbye?
维克托 我们是搭档
Viktor, you're my partner.
你我早就分道扬镳了
Our paths diverged long ago.
只不过基于友谊
It was affection
才走到今天
that held us together.
你以为我好受吗
You think it's so easy?
背负着全城人寄予的厚望却置之不理
To turn your back while your city looks to you for salvation?
眼看着好友命悬一线却心有余悸
To cling to principles while your best friend bleeds out
不敢放手相救
in your arms?
我就该承受这些吗
I never asked for this.
你要上哪儿去
Where are you going?
再见了 杰斯
Goodbye, Jayce.
人越来越多了
There's so many of them.
帮派火拼
It's all the fighting.
这里装不下多少人了
We're gonna have capacity issues soon.
而且还有安全隐患
Then there's the security risk.
那也不能把他们拒之门外
We're not turning people away.
这么多年
All these years,
好不容易摆脱了希尔科
we finally get rid of Silco,
结果却是换个人继续走老路
just so a new one can take his place.
看好了
Now watch this.
这可真让人头大啊
Oh, this is quite troubling.
那棵树对我们来说非常重要
That tree means so much.
我们的食物 新鲜的空气
It's our food. Fresh air.
我们生存的一切都来自于它We built our whole identity around it.
每次以为能松口气的时候就会...
Every time it seems like we might catch a break...
好啦 总会有办法的嘛
Ah, now, it's not lost yet, lad.
要是有法子救这棵树
If there is a means of preservation,
祖师爷啊 我们一定能找到的
by golly, we'll find it.
这种状态的东西我以前见过
I have seen something of this nature before.
去去去
Ch-ch-ch.
这里
Hmm.
你不是说是你的地盘吗
Don't you essentially own this place?
嘘
Shh.
跟我来
Come on.
红霸符已经离开野区
The brambleback has left the jungle.
你难道不知道这样现编暗号 别人是听不懂的吗
Uh, you do realize code phrases don't work when you make them up on the spot?
教授
Professor?
对啊 不然呢
Yes, of course.
你这是搞什么名堂啊你
What the devil's gotten into you?
我还以为...
I thought...
你闯进我的实验室干吗
Why are you breaking into my lab?
他又是谁
And who's he?
他是我新收的学生艾克
This is my new pupil, Ekko.
艾克 这是我以前的学生杰斯
Ekko, my former pupil Jayce.
我很抱歉突然造访
I apologize for the intrusion.
我们本打算悄悄溜进来的
We were attempting to sneak in.
得了吧 就好像你没干过似的
Oh, pishposh. Like you've never done it.
你是住在这儿了吗
Were you sleeping here?
要不要来杯茶 艾克
You drink tea, Ekko?
没错
You're right.
腐蚀情况跟用海克斯核心 测试的植物一致
It matches the corruption we saw on the plants we tested with the Hexcore,
不过你们是在哪儿发现的来着
but where did you say you found this?
就在我们底城深处
Deep in the underground.
艾克的家乡是个不同寻常的地方
Ekko's home is a marvelous place.
惊为天人
Truly a wonder.
你真该去看看的
- You should see what-- -  Hey.
对 我说的家乡 当然是指他心灵的归属
Uh, right, uh, when I said "home," I was, of course, referring to his cognitive center.
反正肯定不可能 是什么真实存在的地方
Not a physical location hidden in the...
黑默丁格
Heimer,
- 而且更不可能还藏在... - 你说什么呢
what are you doing?
植物有存活下来的吗
Did any of the plants survive?
当时都没有顾得上考虑
They weren't what we were trying to save.
但这个纹路
But this pattern.
怎么可能两个城都有出现
How could it be there and here?
不是吧
Oh, no.
维克托去哪儿了
Where's Viktor?
臭小子往哪跑
找死吗你
老实点儿
滚一边儿去
记住了吗
维克托
Viktor.
确定没人
It's all clear.
抱歉 长官
Sorry, commander.
蓝发小妞
Baby Blue.
你还真是难逮啊
Right through their fingers.
你是属泥鳅的吧
You must be part eel.
这回我可得狮子大开口了
Just means I can up my finder's fee.
有商有量才叫生意嘛
There's always a deal to be struck.
别动 他们是要留活口
Ah, ah, ah. They want you alive.
可没说不能把你的眼珠子挖出来
But don't think I won't skewer out those peepers.
看你这种长手的该怎么办
Drawback of you long-range types.
我呢 我比较喜欢靠得近一点
Me? I'm the kind of guy who likes to get in close.
没想到你还会哭鼻子
Never thought I'd catch you blubbering.
希尔科见没见过你这个样子
Wonder if Silco even saw that.
两回
Twice.
一回是刚见面
When he met me
一回是我杀了他
and when I killed him.
是你
You?
回回都是我
It's always me.
就算不是我动的手
Whether I'm pulling the pin or not,
但凡有人靠近我的身边 也都得死
everyone who gets close to me dies.
明白我的意思了吧
Wanna know the real kicker?
你不是说你还是喜欢靠得近一点吗
You're the kind of guy who likes to get in close.
慢着 慢着
Okay, wait, wait, wait. There's a deal to be struck here.
做生意得有商有量的
提醒你一下 你可就那么一次机会
You forget, Smeech? You already made your last offer.
你说凤凰掉了毛不如什么来着
Tell me, who's a funny-looking rat now?
你怎么会来这儿
Fancy meeting you here.
这蠢货永远都管不住自己那张臭嘴
Moron never could keep his damn mouth shut.
干嘛不让我自生自灭
You could've just let me eat it.
嫌我照顾你的还不够啊
Haven't I done you enough favors?
我没让你做这个
I didn't ask you for this.
这些不过就是顺手的事
It was something I could fix.
你又是一副那种表情
You got that look in your eye again.
在打什么主意
What are you planning?
有些家里的事情需要了结
To finish what's left of my family.
维克托
Viktor.
小心别把装备刮坏了
Careful not to scrape up the gear.
不然就卖不出去了
Won't sell as well.
我也不想伤害你
Nothing personal, friend.
我们实在也是没有办法
We just got needs we can't ignore.
这种痛苦毫无意义
So much senseless pain.
你想干什么
What are you doing?
你们不必再受苦了
You need not suffer anymore.
可是
But...
字幕翻译: 付博文 韩一旻